Joseph St. Jean Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
Joseph St. Jean Archives
1913-1957
IPAR.002443
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
3
The archives of Joseph St. Jean. These include photographs, systematic indices, bibliographies, and other auxiliary material related to his study of the Stromatoporoidea.
St. Jean, Joseph
Biographical Sketch
Indiana University PhD, 1956. "Middle Devonian Stromatoporoidea from Indiana, Kentucky, and Ohio."
Description of the Material
Auxiliary material related to his study of the Stromatoporoidea including photographs and negatives, systematic indices, bibliographies, locality descriptions, and correspondence.
Yale University
- Photographs & Negatives, Series I
  - Photographs & Negatives. Negatives from Galloway, J. J. Stored in an Eastman Negative Album. Most of foraminifera., 002446
    - Photographs and negatives from "IPR.06115 - Galloway, Jesse J. & Ehlers, George M. 1960. Some Middle Devonian stromatoporoids from Michigan and southwestern Ontario, including the types described by Alexander Winchell and A.W. Grabau. Contributions from the Museum of Paleontology, University of Michigan. 15: 39-120.", 002433
    - Negatives from Galloway, J. J. Stored in an Eastman Negative Album. Most of foraminifera., 002434
    - Black and white photographs of foraminifera (Camerina javana, Discocyclina javana, D. omphalus, D. bi, 002439
    - A series of photograph + negative + identification for the following species: Aphralysia cabonaria Garweed, Aulacera nodulosa (Billings), Stachyodes ramosa Bargatsky, Stromatopora concentrica Goldfuss, Syringostroma densum Nicholson, Ludictyon vesiculosum Ozaki, Cryptophragmus antiquatus Raymond, Dendrostroma oculatum (Nicholson), Sinodictyon columnare Yabe and Sugiyama, Labechiella regularis, Pseudolabechia granulata Yabe and Sugiyama, Chalazodes granulatum Parks, Clavidictyon columnare Sugiyama, Clathrodictyon columnare Sugiyama, Stromatoporella granulata (Nicholson), Actinostroma clathratum Nicholson, Dendrostroma papillata (James), Gerronostroma butschatense Yavorski, Stromatopora (Epistromatopora) torinosuensis Yabe and Sugiyama, Pseudostylodictyon poshanensis Ozaki, Lophiostroma schmidti (Nicholson), Kentlandia imbricata Schrock, Thamnobeatricea parallela Raymond, Labechia (Labechiella) serotina Nicholson, Hermatostroma sohluteri Nicholson, Stromatocerium rugosum Hall, 002453
    - Black and white photographs of stromatoporoids, mostly thin sectioned specimens. Specimens identified on the back of the photographs by taxon, locality, and slide number. Contains photos of the following slides: 235/2, 235/11, 235/12, 235/23, 278/5, 278/21, 279/2, 279/3, 279/6, 282/1, 282/3, 282/4, 282/8,9,10,11, 282/10, 282/12, 282/13, 282/18, 282/19, 282/20, 282/22, 282/23, 282/26, 282/29,30,31,32,34, 282/35,36, 282/38, 282/44, 282/47, 282/52, 282/53, 282/54, 282/55, 282/57, 282/58, 282/66, 282/72, 282/75, 282/82, 282/83, 282/86, 282/88, 282/90, 282/91, 282/95, 282/97, 282/98, 285/1, 285/2, 285/3, 285/4, 285/6,7, 285/8,9,10, 285/10, 285/11, 285/14,15,16,17,31, 285/14, 285/15, 285/16, 285/17, 285/18,19, 285/24, 285/25, 285/26, 285/27,28,29, 285/27, 285/29, 285/49, 285/52, 285/55, 285/74, 285/76, 285/80, 285/94, 285/95, 294/4, 294/5, 294/8,9, 294/8, 294/9, 294/14,23,24, 294/15, 294/26, 294/29, 294/63, 294/67, 294/85, 294/97, 294/98, 295/7, 295/8, 295/23, 295/24, 295/25, 295/44, 295/45, 002466
    - Black and white photograph of YPM 9200.B, Aulacera nodulifera (Foerste)., 002467
    - Negatives of stromatoporoids, plates, thin sections, and specimens., 002468
- Miscellaneous, Series II
  - Bibliographies., 002437
    - Bibiliography of Foraminifera. Printed on 4 x 6" cards. Includes the following categories: Stratigraphy (Upper Cretaceous - Eocene), Geology (North and South America), Smaller Foraminifera (Lower Cretaceous), Smaller Foraminifera (Upper Cretaceous), Heterohelicidae, Globotruncana and Globigerina, Smaller Forams (Tertiary), Larger Foraminifera (Tertiary), Conical Rotalids (mainly India), Calcarinidae, Larger Foraminifera (Cretaceous and Tertiary), Discocyclinidae, Lepidorbitoidinae, Orbitoidinae, Pseudoorbitoidinae, Incerte [sic] sedis, Genetics, Various Literature Forams., 002469
  - Correspondence., 002458
    - Correspondence about stromatoporoid specimens, loans, and reprints., 002459
    - Correspondence between Galloway and other authors regarding stromatoporoids, 002928
  - Miscellaneous., 002436
    - Listing of students receiving doctors of philosophy in geology at Indiana University, 1913-1942; 002456
    - Geological Survey of Canada type fossils figured in Galloway and St. Jean, 1961 (IPR.06082), 002947
    - Handout from the University of Kentucky Field Conference around Lexington, KY, 22 Jun 1945 - 24 Jun 1945; 002946
    - Excerpt from "Structure and classification of the Stromatoporoidea" J. J. Galloway, Indiana University, January 1957. Excerpt includes the systematic descriptions., 002435
    - Correspondence and non-published data about possible stromatoporoids in Alberta, 002452
    - Assorted measurements of and notes about stromatoporoids., 002454
    - Information about Michigan sections around Traverse Bay and stromatoporoids found there., 002457
    - Copy of a manuscript. "Alexander Winchell's and A. W. Grabau's types of Michigan Devonian Stromatoporoidea", 002460
    - Locality descriptions and stratigraphic sections, Indiana., 002462
    - Miscellaneous notes and descriptions of stromatoporoid species., 002463
    - Card catalog associated with Foraminifera slide collection., 002464
    - Card catalog associated with Ostracoda slide collection., 002465
    - Manuscript (possibly student project) entitled "Anemone Mud Ball." Included with Galloway's papers., 002722
    - Manuscript material; Detroit River Stromatoporoidea, 002933
    - Translated and annotated manuscript of IPR.06486. Stromatoporoidea Sovetskogo Soyuza, 002934
    - list of Middle Devonian stromatoporoids of the lower Mackenzie Valley, collected by A. C. Lenz in 1958, identified by J. Galloway in 1959. Princeton University specimen numbers included., 002937
    - Assorted ephemera from J. J. Galloway including old work orders and loan forms, 002938
    - list of localities (presumably of stromatoporoids) labeled 1D-1449D, 002945
  - Saskatchewan Stromatoporoidea., 002450
    - Notes for a presentation and a manuscript on the "Stromatoporoidea of the Souris River Fm., from the subsurface of Saskatchewan.", 002448
    - Correspondence regarding the Stromatoporoidea of the Souris River Fm., Saskatchewan., 002449
    - Auxiliary material and non-published data regarding the Stromatoporoidea of the Souris River Fm., Saskatchewan., 002451
  - Systematic Indices., 002447
    - Systematic key to the Order Aseptata Grabau (Tabulata Milne-Edwards and Haime), 002438
    - Handwritten index cards from the Atlantis 1947 research cruise, listing ostracods from the Gulf of Mexico. By W. T. Rothwell, Jr. These were in St. Jean's foram collection., 002440
    - Handwritten index cards. Original author unknown, these were in St. Jean's foram collection. Foraminifera and diatom genera and slides on which they're found., 002441
    - Handwritten index cards. Original author unknown, these were in St. Jean's foram collection. Alphabetic listing of genera and the slides on which they're found., 002442
    - Index of North American species of Devonian Stromatoporoids and other recently published forms., 002455
    - Systematic index for European stromatoporoids., 002461
- Locality information, Series III
  - Locality information., 002932
    - Localities of Devonian rocks in northern Michigan recorded by the Geological Survey of Michigan and the Museum of Paleontology atthe University of Michigan, 002929
    - Assorted locality information: Devonian of Indiana and Ohio, 002936
  - Maps., 002931
    - USGS 7.5' quadrangle: Jeffersonville, IN-KY. 1:24,000 scale. 1951 edition. Annotated with localities., 002944
    - Map of Vermont; issued by the Vermont Development Commission and Department of Highways. Annotated with localities., 1953; 002943
    - Map of Charlevoix County, MI. Annotated with localities., 002939
    - Map of Presque Isle County, MI; issued by the Presque Isle County Road Commission. Annotated with localities., 002940
    - Map of Emmet County, MI; issued by the Emmet County Road Commission. Annotated with localities., 002941
    - Map of Alpena County, MI; issued by the Alpena County Road Commission. Annotated with localities., 002942